♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Atoy] Ah, sorry,
I just got distracted by your bag.
But it looks like it's missing a stud…
like this?
What puzzles me more,
is if it's true,
then what was her motive?
Was Martina in the office the other day?
[Ria] Yes.
I have a picture…
You can see her in the background.
I saw it under the console table
when I cleaned.
[attorney] There are many bags
with studs like this.
Looks like Attorney is right, 'Son.
Are you sure she believed
I was in the office?
Of course, ma'am.
I even showed her the selfie,
while you were busy at work.
I was there. I couldn't do anything, bro!
And now, I'm just looking
for someone to blame!
[Paldo] Stop blaming yourself.
What's wrong with you?
[Audrey, in English] I want to apologize.
[in English] For accusing me
of killing Tonet,
or for being so hateful
towards me and your brother?
But just because we're family
doesn't mean I'll side with what's wrong.
Mommy, let's just go on vacation.
And my birthday is coming soon.
Let's celebrate there instead?
[in English] Okay, my dear. Yes.
[in English] Um, wherever you want to go.
Come on, let's go to the room, baby, okay?
Don't cry anymore.
PREVIOUSLY
[music swells]
[music fades]
[crickets chirping in the distance]
[Ibyang] Sister Tonet.
Sister Tonet.
Please show yourself to me.
Yoo-hoo!
You haven't gone up to heaven yet, right?
You were just buried.
Maybe you want a midnight snack.
Puff pastry, your favorite.
[frantic music playing]
Sister Tonet?
Is that you?
[music swells]
[shrieks]
[Atoy] Son of a thread.
Ibyang, what are you doing here?
It's midnight.
Why aren't you asleep?
And what's with the candles?
What are you doing now?
I want Sister Tonet
to let me feel her presence.
[melancholic music playing]
Miss Cita said
she showed herself
to Brother Emerson in the hospital,
so…
I'm calling her.
I brought her favorite puff pastry.
Ibyang.
You can't just call a person's soul
like you're calling a dog,
okay?
I just wanted to try.
I miss Sister Tonet.
Why did she leave us so soon?
I wish I knew the answer to that.
But one thing I'm sure of, Ibyang,
no matter what happens,
I will never abandon you,
and I will never leave you.
[sentimental music playing]
Okay?
All right.
Go to sleep now. Go up to your room.
Go.
[Ibyang] Okay.
[Atoy, in English] Good night.
[music fades]
[phone vibrating]
Hello?
Who's this?
Janine.
Oh, why?
What's the problem?
[suave theme music playing]
[music concludes]
- [Gemma] Welcome to Amor Fati Lake resort,
- Oh wow!
- [Audrey] Thank you.
- Ms. Audrey and Ms. Janine!
[in English] I love it.
[in English] Oh, matching!
[in English] Oh, here you go, dear.
- [in English] Cheers!
- Mommy.
[in English] Thank you.
[in English] Anything for you, my dear.
Um, Mommy,
I also have a surprise for you.
Mmm?
- To make this vacation perfect.
- Mmm.
[light music playing]
[Janine] Ta-da!
I invited Daddy.
Atoy?
Mommy, I called Daddy,
so, my birthday
will be our family bonding,
and we'll all be complete.
[titters]
I have another surprise for you.
[Audrey] Ibyang.
[unsettling music]
Ibyang?
Daddy, why is she here?
Janine, she has no one at home.
No one to watch over her.
And also, it's so that
she can relax a bit too.
She's been so sad since Tonet passed away.
I don't like you.
Send her home, Daddy!
She's not part of the family!
Janine, shh.
Janine, don't say that.
Janine, you will be siblings.
I will adopt her.
She will take my surname too.
So, you will be siblings.
No!
I'm your only child, Daddy!
- I'll talk to her.
- I'll handle it.
Janine, come here.
[pensive music playing]
[Atoy] Come here.
Come here.
Janine, I don't like what you're doing.
If you were raised like that before…
it won't work with me now. Okay?
Because I don't want you to grow up a brat
and disrespectful to others.
I want you to apologize to Ibyang
and to your mommy.
[tense music playing]
Janine.
[birds chirping]
[Atoy] Janine?
Janine!
[phone recording, in English] I'm sorry,
all circuits are busy now.
What's this? I can't reach her!
There's no signal here.
What did you say to the child?
I just scolded her a little.
You know kids like that.
They need to be taught lessons early,
so they don't grow up spoiled.
You know,
it's a good thing you're here.
I can't discipline her the way you do.
I see how kind Ibyang is
because of your guidance.
[in English] You know, I think you'll be
a really good father to her.
[light music playing]
That one? [chuckles softly]
She's mischievous too.
I hope you find her a mother.
So you'll have a partner in raising her.
It's not necessary. I can handle it.
Atoy, Ibyang is a girl.
She needs a mother figure.
[in English] You know, someone who will be
a good role model for her.
You should get married.
[music fades]
She idolizes you.
[light music playing]
Um… No, no. I don't mean
you should marry me, okay?
What I mean is, she mentioned to me once
that she looks up to you.
Like she idolizes you,
something like that.
Janine?
Where could she be?
[in English] Ah, um, sir, excuse me.
Did you notice a little girl?
Uh, long hair, eight years old.
- Wearing a pink dr--
- If your child is unruly,
don't bring her here just to lose her.
[in English] Sorry.
I didn't mean for my child to go missing.
You bear a child
and you can't even watch her.
[in English] Good morning, sir!
Gemma! Gemma!
- [Gemma, in English] Yes, ma'am?
- Who was that?
Ah. That was Sir Leon.
Um, that's just how he is.
Mmm, grumpy and weird.
Actually, he's been renting near
your cabin for a month now.
He just doesn't like
being disturbed or hear any noise.
Then why rent here?
He knows there are many guests.
He should've vacationed in a cave instead.
Yes, ma'am.
Uh, I'll go ahead.
I'll look for Janine too.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Hmm-mm.
Where is that girl?
Janine.
[Gemma] Janine?
Hey!
So, you're just here!
Your mommy and daddy are looking for you.
Let them.
Let them look for me.
[unsettling music playing]
Daddy annoys me.
He even brought that annoying Ibyang.
You're just staying here?
All right.
They might go boating without you.
I'll just tell them you're here sulking.
No.
I should be included.
This is my birthday vacation!
[sighs] Then go to your parents.
Apologize to your daddy.
Behave, so you won't
get scolded anymore. Hmm?
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
[Ibyang] Hey, Janine!
Ibyang, let's talk.
It's my birthday.
So, can I be with my parents?
[in English] Uh, okay?
Mmm, you're with them anyway.
[pensive music playing]
Yes, of course.
But I don't want you to come with us!
But Daddy can't send you home.
So, can you, Ibyang…
Just know your place, please.
Give me a moment with my family
because we're the OG family.
This is the only time
I'll be with them, so…
make it your birthday gift to me,
Ibyang, please. Can you?
[pensive music playing]
All right.
[in English] Deal.
[in English] Happy birthday.
Birthday your face!
[Janine] Ouch.
Son of a-- Hey!
[ominous music playing]
So stupid.
Why are you angry?
You're the one who bumped into me.
Hey, you.
I'll fight with kids, okay?
Don't test me!
Sorry.
Please don't be mad at her.
I'll apologize for her.
Hey, don't meddle!
Fine, leave now!
Go!
[music fades]
[tense music playing]
[footsteps tapping]
[snoring]
[Karla] Really now.
Karla!
What's happening?
Don't sleep on the sofa.
Buy me some beer first.
Come on.
[Karla] Don't you want coffee first?
Take a bath, brush your teeth,
look for a job!
Ah, that's easy!
I'll do all that!
Just buy me some liquor
so my headache will go away.
Go on. Buy it.
[pensive music playing]
Oh? What are you waiting for?
My head hurts. To make it go away! Buy it.
[music swells]
[music fades]
Oh, Janine!
- Oh, thank you.
- [Janine] Mommy.
Mommy, wh-- where's Daddy?
[Audrey] He's still looking for you!
[clicks tongue] Janine, child…
Don't get used to always walking out
whenever you don't like
what's being said to you.
Your daddy just wants you
to be raised properly.
[in English] I'm sorry.
Is Daddy still mad at me?
He's not mad at you, dear.
Um, Mommy, Ibyang and I are okay now.
We've reconciled.
I also apologized to her.
[Audrey mutters]
Oh, wow.
[sneaky music playing]
Um, right, Ibyang?
Uh, we're okay now.
We don't want any trouble
during my birthday vacation.
- Right?
- Uh, yes.
We're okay now.
[in English] That's very good.
I'm so happy to hear that.
Let's just forget
what happened earlier, okay?
[in English] We can officially start
your birthday vacation right now!
I'll call your daddy.
I'll tell him we'll meet
at the boating area, okay?
Yay! Let's go boating!
[bright music playing]
[line ringing]
Please.
Don't sell liquor or beer
to my father anymore.
Not even rubbing alcohol.
He's been drunk for days now.
Since he lost his job,
he's just been drinking.
Uh, don't worry. I'll tell my old buddies.
Because I've stopped drinking liquor
since I was forbidden
by San Antonio de Padua.
All right, child. I know the stores here.
I'm already disgusted with him.
He smells so bad. He doesn't bathe.
Um, Karla, if you're
disgusted with the smell,
I have a suggestion, okay? Don't get mad.
Invite your father to drink.
Then, you guys will go against
each other in a shot-drinking contest.
[chuckles]
Ah, Nestor, you're not helping.
Karla, why do you seem unhappy?
Your father is here.
You know, when you were little,
when he didn't come home,
you missed him right away.
Now that he's here,
it's like you want to throw salt at him.
That was before.
I got used to not being noticed.
Often even being hit.
I'd rather he wasn't here.
I never felt like I had a father.
Sir Delfin, I considered him my father.
He and Brother Atoy
are the decent men in my life.
[gentle music playing]
All right. I'll go now.
[music fades]
You and your suggestions. Oh, come on.
My suggestion was fine, right?
- It was a suggestion.
- But not like that.
[bright music playing]
- If we go straight here, is it safe?
- [Ibyang] Tatoy!
I'll row, okay?
[dramatic sting]
Did you forget
your birthday gift to me, Ibyang, huh?
[dramatic sting]
What's that?
Um, she said she won't join the boating.
Oh?
Yes.
I just suddenly got hungry.
Ah, I saw the clubhouse sandwich earlier.
It looked delicious.
Really?
- Yes, she's sure.
- [Atoy] All right.
Ah, Ma-- Marie…
Take care of this child
for the meantime, okay.
- Just feed her.
- Okay.
[Atoy] Maybe three, whatever.
Come on, Janine.
- Let's go?
- [Atoy mutters]
[pensive music playing]
[Audrey] Ahh!
[in English] Thank you.
Oh, slowly, my dear.
- [Janine] Yes.
- [Audrey] There!
[Audrey, in English] Thank you so much.
[melodramatic music playing]
[light music playing]
Why does it feel like we're not moving?
Yes, I noticed that too.
Well, you're rowing that way.
I'm rowing this way.
- [Atoy] I thought--
- We really won't move. Hello?
Aren't we supposed to go there?
[chuckling]
- [Atoy] Oh my.
- Okay, I'll switch.
- [Audrey] I'll move, okay.
- [Atoy] Okay, okay.
[Audrey] Here, here. Okay, okay.
[Atoy grunts]
- Oh? What, here?
- Yes, okay.
- All right, go.
- Oh, let's go there.
[in English] One, two, three, go.
Oh. [squeals]
[Atoy] Oh, sorry.
- [Atoy] Sorry, I didn't--
- What was that?!
Sorry, I didn't mean it.
Ah, so that's how it is? Here, me too.
I didn't mean it either.
- [Atoy] Wait!
- [squeals, then chuckles]
All right, let's go there.
- [Janine] Mommy!
- [in English] Sorry. Time-out, time-out.
Child, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
- [Audrey] Okay.
- Face that way.
That's the dry part.
- [Atoy] Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
- Sorry, sorry, child.
[Audrey squeals] My scarf!
[in English] Oh, no…
- Oh, no. It's expensive--[squeals]
- [Atoy] Oh my.
[Atoy] There, it's sinking!
- [Audrey] Oh my!
- Oh!
It's just a scarf.
[Audrey] Okay, I can do this.
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Come here, come here.
[in English] Got it. Almost got it!
- Mommy--
- [Audrey squeals]
[Janine] Mommy! Daddy, Mommy!
Let her. She can handle it!
[Atoy grunts]
Mommy.
[music fades]
Mommy!
Daddy.
Daddy!
Audrey?
[ominous music playing]
Mommy!
[foreboding music playing]
Audrey?
Audrey!
Mommy!
Mommy?
Audrey!
[in English] I found it!
I found it! [pants]
I just swam because…
the water's cold.
Son of a thread!
You scared us. We thought
something happened to you!
I know how to swim.
I lived on the island for a long time.
Did you forget?
Well, how would I know?
You've changed, right?
For all I know, you forgot how to swim.
[in English] I may have a different name,
but I'm still the same girl
you met back then, Anthony.
[light music playing]
[in English] Race you back!
[chuckles softly]
[music fades]
You know, I still wonder
why Mom puts up with Dad.
She's used to him not being around.
We're happier when he's not here.
Hmm…
Maybe your dad is your mom's true love.
That's why she puts up with everything,
because they've been
through a lot together.
Sis, I don't think so.
Well, aren't there couples like that?
They stay together,
even if they don't love
each other anymore,
because they're just used to it.
It's convenient.
And maybe your mom
is afraid of growing old alone.
[melanchoic music playing]
- [sighs]
- [Karla] Oh?
- Mom!
I thought you weren't going to work.
I have something to finish.
And your father left.
Said he'd look for a job.
Good thing!
Um, Miss Cita, how about you?
Didn't you ever think of leaving,
look for another job?
Or maybe starting your own tailoring shop?
I'm happy here.
And Delfin asked me to guide Atoy.
He and his wife Julie
were my best friends.
So, I'm just fulfilling my promise.
Um, Miss Cita,
if you and Sir Delfin were single then,
do you think you could've been together?
[Karla] I wish that were the case, right?
Then Brother Atoy
and I would be your children.
[Ame] Mmm-mmm.
[Karla chuckles softly]
[mellow music playing]
- Oh, thank you.
- [Atoy grunts]
- Um…
- [groans]
- All right, all right.
- Oh.
Um, no.
- It's okay. It's yours now.
- [Atoy] Here, here. Use it, use it.
[Janine] My daddy is so sweet!
Ayiee!
- [Janine giggles]
- [Audrey] Janine…
Janine-- Come here.
You need to change.
Tatoy, there's a horseback
riding activity here.
I want to ride a horse.
Really?
All right.
Go ahead first. I'll just change.
[in English] Yes!
[tense music playing]
Uh, little girl, hmm,
we'll just take a 40-minute break, okay?
We'll also feed the horses first.
Are you alone?
Uh, no.
I'm waiting for my father.
He's taking so long.
Mmm. Better go to him first.
Just come back later.
Ah, yes.
[pensive music playing]
[Audrey] Atoy, Atoy!
Don't leave yet. Stay here first.
Um, Janine requested that
we surprise her with a birthday cake.
She requested a surprise?
How will that be a surprise?
Um, just let it be.
She's been a good girl today.
And…
There she is. She's coming out!
- Oh.
- Give it to me.
Light it now.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, happy birthday ♪
Thank you, Mommy and Daddy.
[in English] Don't forget to make a wish
before you blow your candle, dear.
I wish my parents would get back together,
so our family of three will be complete!
- Wow!
- [staff] Yay!
Oh, were you surprised?
[chuckles softly]
- Oh, let's take a picture!
- [indistinct]
- [in English] Let's go, let's go.
[staff] We'll post it
on our social media page.
- [Audrey] Okay.
- [Atoy] Yes.
Smile, child! Happy birthday!
[in English] Thank you.
[in English] One, two, three!
Say, "Happy family!"
- [all, in English] Happy family!
- [camera shutter snaps]
[staff, in English] One more, one more.
Mommy, Daddy, kiss each other.
- [Atoy] Huh?
- Oh?
- [Janine] Please kiss, please.
- Yiee, they'll get back together!
[teasing]
- [titters]
- Get back together?
- [Janine] Please.
- [mutters]
- Huh?
- Kiss, kiss each other. Please, kiss.
- Kiss.
- Hey, kiss. Your child is requesting.
- [staff] I'll take another picture.
- On the cheeks only, okay?
Of course. Why,
did you want it on the lips?
Stop it, Atoy.
- All right.
- Okay, kiss.
- [staff, in English] One, two, three.
- [camera shutter snaps]
[staff, in English] Hold it, hold it.
[camera shutter snaps]
Oh, come on. You too.
Oh, one more. One more.
One, two--
Oh, that's enough.
[tense music playing]
UP NEXT
She's the one who threw it, not me!
You lying child!
[cracks]
I didn't like what you did to my child.
[man] You're the mother of that child?
No wonder she's unruly.
You're arrogant.
You think you're somebody.
[Ibyang] Let's not follow them.
That person is dangerous.
[Ibyang] He has a gun.
Are you his wife?
[dramatic stinging]
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias